<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>ayanbag</title>
		<description>  ase @ tcs</description>
		<link></link>
		<atom:link href="/rss-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>What is A-Star Algorithm ?</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Ayan Bag</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Star Algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the most popular computer algorithm widely used in Path-finding and Graph Traversal. This algorithm efficiently search and plots a path between multiple nodes, or points, on the graph. It is used in various applications, such as &lt;em&gt;Maps&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/a-star-algorithms</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-star-algorithms</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Unbeatable Tic-Tac-Toe with Minimax Algorithm</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Ayan Bag</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Since the advent of Artificial Algorithms, the game playing has been one of the most interesting part of Artificial Intelligence. In 1947, a computer named “Deep Blue” defeated reigning world chess champion Garry Kasprov is a defining moment in the history of AI. But the great minds behind this computer started investing and publishing in this subject nearly six decades earlier. &lt;strong&gt;Alan Turing&lt;/strong&gt; known as the father of theoretical algorithm and artificial intelligence is credited with provoking the investigation dating all the way back to the 1940s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/minimax-algorithm</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/minimax-algorithm</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sieve of Eratosthenes Algorithm - the ancient algorithm</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Ayan Bag</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sieve of Eratosthenes&lt;/strong&gt; is a simple and ancient algorithm to find thr prime number up to a given limit. This is one of the most efficient algorithm to find small prime numbers. This algorithm for collecting primes numbers is invented by Eratosthenes (276 - 194 BC).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/sieve-of-eratothenes-algo</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/sieve-of-eratothenes-algo</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Floyd Cycle Detection Algorithm</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Ayan Bag</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-loop-in-linked-list-&quot;&gt;What is Loop in Linked List ?&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/floyd-cycle-detection-algorithm</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/floyd-cycle-detection-algorithm</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Ramer–Douglas–Peucker Algorithm</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Ayan Bag</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Ramer–Douglas–Peucker Algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; is a an algorithms that reduce the number of points that is approximated by a series of points. It is also known as the &lt;strong&gt;Douglas–Peucker algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;iterative end-point fit algorithm&lt;/strong&gt;. In simple words, it represent a complex line with fewer points in a visually proper way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/rdp-algo</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/rdp-algo</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Understanding Linked List in Python</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Ayan Bag</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linked List&lt;/strong&gt; is a list of elements (containing data) in which the elements are linked together. In other words, it is an ordered collection of elements. It differ from the list in the way we store elements. Unlike list, Linked List doesn’t store its elements at contiguous memory locations.
In Linked List, each link contains a connection to another link. Linked List is the second most-used data structure after array.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/linked-list</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/linked-list</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why to use Strict Mode in JavaScript ?</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Ayan Bag</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript &lt;strong&gt;strict mode&lt;/strong&gt; is a new feature in ECMAScript 5 that enables us to code a program, or a method in a “strict” operating context. It means, the errors which are being ignored by the compiler, will throw an exception message. It is a way to opt into a restricted version of JavaScript i.e implicitly opting-out of “sloppy mode”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/strict-mode-in-js</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/strict-mode-in-js</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Kickstart to Machine Learning with Sckit-learn</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Ayan Bag</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sckit-learn&lt;/strong&gt; is a open source Python library that provides many unsupervised and supervised learning algorithms. It also  implements a range of preprocessing, cross-validation and visualization algorithms using a unified interface&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/sckit-learn</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/sckit-learn</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Introduction to Multi-threading in Python</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Ayan Bag</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Like multiprocessing, multithreading is a way of achieving multitasking. Most of the code we write in Python is single threaded. A python virtual machine runs behind the scene uses a thread called the &lt;strong&gt;main thread&lt;/strong&gt; i.e &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;main()&lt;/code&gt; to execute the code which has written.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/multi-threading</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/multi-threading</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Sweet Introduction to R Programming</title>
				
					<dc:creator>Ayan Bag</dc:creator>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;R is a open source and very popular programming language and environment for statistical computer and graphics.R was designed by statisticians and was specialized for statistical computing, and thus is known as the &lt;strong&gt;lingua franca of statistics&lt;/strong&gt;. It is mostly used in Data Science and Machine Learning. It is managed by R core development team — team of volunteer developer from across the globe. R provide a wide variety of statistical and graphical techniques and highly extensible.It was developed at Bell Laboratories by John Chambers and colleagues.R is a consolidated environment for performing statistical operation and generating R data analysis reports in graphical or text formats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/intro-to-r</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/intro-to-r</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
